Gary B. Genett

Seattle, WA • 206-391-6606 • me@garybgenett.net • www.linkedin.com/in/gary-b-genett

Senior Product Manager

Organizational Change | Project Management | Product Ownership

Goal-focused professional with 15+ years' success driving all aspects of product ownership, project management, and organizational change to cultivate organizational growth within pressurized environments. Strong ability to build and lead teams that meet and exceed established goals and expectations. Highly adept at developing and implementing controls, processes, and best practices that enhance operational efficiency and mitigate risks. Well-versed in GNU/Linux, cloud architecture, and automation. Demonstrated ability to guide full product and project management lifecycle, from scope definition and initial planning to final delivery, to ensure on-time, on-budget, and on-target results.

Core Competencies

- Technical Project Management
- Team Building and Leadership
- Delivery Management
- Scope Definition & Planning
- Release Management
- Stakeholder Engagement
- Full Product Development Lifecycle
- DevOps / Agile / Waterfall / Scrum
- Product Support, Sales, & Training
- Source Tree Management
- Program & Schedule Management
- Cross-functional Collaboration
- Change Management/Transformation
- Performance & Functional Testing
- Requirements Gathering
- System & Process Optimization
- Budget Management
- Product Strategy & Roadmap

Professional Experience

Alaska Airlines – Seattle, WA

Senior Technical Project Manager, 2019 to Present

Spearheaded the design, coordination, delivery, and oversight of Integration Program environments to ensure that teams are able to efficiently and effectively complete work in a hybrid agile/waterfall workspace. Collaborated cross-functionally to comprehend requirements and define clear scope for environment usage and planning. Played a key role in project scoping and planning, documentation, systems maintenance and downtime planning, and continuous improvement. Prevented disruptions to project progress by identifying and escalating risks well in advance.

Key Contributions:

- Drove the definition and management of environment requirements and calendar across the Integration Program for systems and processes to ensure smooth integration between Alaska Airlines and Virgin America.
- Strengthened controls and overall quality of outcomes by establishing and implementing best practices for delivery of high-quality standard, scalable environments.

Enviro-Master – Seattle, WA

President, 2016 to 2019

Leveraged strong leadership abilities and strategic thinking to lead a high-performing team to deliver all daily operations with attention-to-detail, efficiency, and excellence.

Key Contributions:

• Achieved a high level of customer satisfaction, directing nearly 100 sites across the Puget Sound region.

- Directly doubled sales by increasing sites by 50%, resulting in an additional \$100K in revenue.
- Reduced operational budget to optimize profitability, following the acquisition of failing Swisher business.

F5 Networks – Seattle, WA

Senior Product Management Engineer, 2014 to 2016

Guided the end-to-end product management lifecycle to completion within budget constraints and deadline. Demonstrated ownership and effective advocacy to the executive team to achieve a high-standard of support and fulfil budget goals. Leveraged external and internal relationships, influence, and expertise to direct product strategy and roadmap to accomplish delivery targets.

Key Contributions:

- Built an integral new cloud/orchestration team to ensure smooth operations and optimal productivity amid evolving organizational dynamics.
- Established and drove a new vision for automation, integrating all existing technologies into a unified suite.
- Remained at the forefront of changing market trends and anticipated customer needs to develop direction.

New Product Introduction Engineer, 2009 to 2014

Guaranteed a high standard of preparation and readiness across sales and services organizations ahead of new product and service releases. Ensured clear communication channels and optimal operational efficiency as a liaison between the company's major departments, including marketing, development, services, and sales functions. Closed integral deals and optimized retention by performing customer visits with account teams as corporate representative.

Key Contributions:

- Established detailed in-person and web-based training for each release and new technology to maximize product knowledge.
- Spearheaded the effective milestone release of 5 innovative technologies and deep product rewrite.
- Steered the internal homegrown heuristics tool to pre-analyze customer diagnostic files for the support team through initial stages to customer-facing product.
- Reduced production time from several weeks to a few days and increased retention by pioneering innovative video-based training format.
- Designed and presented comprehensive internal product sessions at international sales and services conferences.

Field Systems Engineer - Technical Sales, 2006 to 2009

Delivered high-quality support to thousands of devices during the development of Azure public cloud. Built and strengthened key professional relationships and provided comprehensive support for technical work, resulting in MSNBC case study.

Key Contributions:

- Significantly grew customer adoption as primary engineering representative on Microsoft account team.
- Increased customer device count by 300% and revenue by 400% with only 2 additional team members.
- Pioneered detailed integration guide and training to aid 3rd party development and improve quality and efficiency.
- Initiated and directed 2 successful production deployments of revolutionary chassis architectures for Xbox Live.

Product Management Engineer, 2004 to 2006

Established a high-caliber new team to perform all key duties within time constraints, including developing roles and responsibilities and creating templates for deliverables and reports. Played a key role in steering the overall product strategy and building prototype solutions to solve technical challenges.

$Key\ Contributions:$

- Led the initial analysis, guidance, and testing for 3 successive company acquisitions.
- Drove the successful development of a Performance Testing Guide, setting the industry standard for comprehensive review.
- Expertly released SSL VPN for UNIX-like systems, as Perl script and Video Demonstration of Process.

Additional experience as **Network Support Engineer** for F5 Networks, **Implementation Specialist** for MI-CROS Systems, **UNIX Tier 3 Support Specialist** for HostPro, and **Operations and Systems Production Support** for VoiceStream Wireless.

Education and Certification

Perl Programming Course, University of Washington, Seattle, WA Computer Programming Courses, Seattle Central College, Seattle, WA

Technical Proficiencies

Node.js, Python, C, Bash, Perl, TCL, Web Development, HTML/CSS/Javascript, Web/System APIs, REST/J-SON/XML, SQL, Git, SVN, DevOps, Agile, Waterfall, Scrum